this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at sc-radio.net
ski radio is brought to you by the IEEE
computer Society IEEE software Magazine
online at computer.org software
hi all this is your host and
concept of soft
with Nick Manson on identity
management systems Nick is a SAS
architect with over two decades of
experience in Building Sales service and
marketing applications these projects
have included big data analytics data
science Mobile customer relationship
management enterprise resource planning
commas call center and content
integration Nick Labs working with teams
and staying on top of Industry Trends to
build valuable services this episode is
from the perspective of next study and
experience with identity management
systems to architect several of oracle's
cloud and mobile products Nick welcome
to the show great to have you here is
there anything else you'd like to add to
your bio I know you didn't absolutely
excellent job of that kanchan thanks a
lot and thanks for inviting me to
software engineering radio you're
welcome before we start I'd like to
mention a few related episodes we've
done in the past episode 4 92 Sam Scott
on building a consistent and Global
authorization service
episode 376 Justin richer on API
security with or2
episode 383 Neil Madden on securing your
API so Nick we work together over a
decade ago on Sybil ceremont man and I
still remember your statement from them
that the design of the system started
with the user so I'd like to First jump
into basic definitions
what is a digital identity
what is identity management and then
I'll have a follow-up about how we
actually use these Technologies every
day with what identities
sure
a digital identity is an entity within a
computer system that represents an
external agent for the system so that's
a two-part definition for the entity
just think of a record in a data store
most typical example of a digital
identity will be a user record
so we often just refer to digital
identities within our systems as the
users for the external agent think of a
caller for your services that might be a
rest client or web browser that's
operated directly by the end user when
the external agent is manually operated
we often just skip it when we talk about
it and just think of the user as being
the agent
so digital identity typical case a user
has a digital identity that is a user
record
as mediated by a web browser agent if we
go on to identity management identity
management system it's just the part of
your computer system that deals with
establishing and managing digital
identities so any application that knows
something about individual users has
some form of identity management in it
and some applications they'll build that
directly in without thinking about it
some are going to use embedded services
and many Cloud applications will
integrate an independent identity as a
service provider so what are the
different types of identities that we
probably assume every day and use
identity management Technologies maybe
starting with that will help with some
of the follow-up questions sure so most
common case is cloud users
we encounter identity management digital
identity whenever we establish an
account for an online service
so in that case the identity management
system it's collecting that basic
information about Who We Are it's
allowing us to securely set a password
and it's handling the login page those
are the parts that we see if you're
looking at it from a developer
perspective just to flip the coin we'll
encounter identity management when we
wrap our web pages in a filter and have
it redirect to a login page in order to
get force a sign on before they can see
what the servlet's provided we'll also
run into it when we're checking for
authentication before running a service
so that might be checking a bearer token
on a rest request or it might be looking
at a session identifier on a web page
request
and then the last place we might run
into it once you've got authentication
once you have that identity off the
bearer token or the session you might
make a call out to an identity service
to get further information about the
user that you're dealing with so that's
the most common case now there's a few
others simpler but less common
organizations or business flows they can
have digital identities
so that case there's normally a public
private key pair associated with some
named it's often a business flow but
we'll call it a partner organization and
the identity management system handles
managing the public key to go with
private key so that when the
organization's agent sends a rest call
to us we can use that credential to
check the sources from the organization
that we think it is
another case you can use identity
management to track applications and
devices so bring your own device
registration its identity management for
devices that's one way to think of it
there are other things involved there
but it has a digital identity it works a
lot like the organization additionally
there are there can be a lot more
complexity in the flow
Workforce identity management
allows one of the registered people one
of the identities that you pick up to
serve as
the manager for a group of employees and
control the registration of the rest of
the digital identities in their group
banking systems use a digital identity
in the banking system there's often a
point where it says well you've gone
this far but you can't go further until
you come into the bank and show a teller
your driver's license you know maybe a
passport or your last hydro bill so
there's an actual know your customer
component to that with a human workflow
attached to the identity management in
that onboarding process and it's very
common for the identity management flow
to be set up in complicated arrangements
so that they're Federated especially
with Enterprise computing
and an Enterprise Computing situation
the Enterprise will have an identity
management system you'll have an
identity management system and your
system will trust their system for
identifying particular users so what do
you mean by the Enterprise and then you
what is you in this case Okay so being
that this is for engineers when I say
you I'm typically thinking of you the
developer and your service on the cloud
so remembering again that most Cloud
applications have some idea who their
users are so in this case Nick you're
actually alluding to two systems and
that's why you said there was Federation
can you clarify yeah sure so cloud
services often have some concept of
their users they'll have some form of
user management going on and that's
really it's a very small all identity
management system what happens in
Enterprise identity management
really usually in coordination with
Workforce identity management
is the identity management system will
establish some rules
under which it will accept users
authenticated by odd Federated a
separate identity management system
that's under control of someone else
entirely
so in that case
the customers identity management system
big company will have a list of
employees and will be set up to assert
those identities for your services
identity management service and your
service will say I can receive
identities from this system over here
using this public key and the identities
I receive and allow must have the
following characteristics
so Federation across two systems okay
that makes sense thank you
so besides this what are the goals of an
identity management system where does
access management fit in yeah breaking
that into two this is where it begins to
get a little bit more fun and a little
bit less dry
so fundamentally an identity management
system its purpose is to provide a basis
for trust if you think back in the
beginning
it used to be that the person who ran an
application was the person who created
the data for the application and the
person who produced the code all
together as one and that's been broken
up especially with cloud services three
entirely separate people multiple people
working on the same data we need a way
to establish trust and that's what the
identity management system does it gives
us confidence that the caller of our
service speaking from the point of view
of a developer of a cloud service is the
user that we think they are
and we have an identifier for them that
we can associate with the parts of our
application build rules around
so at the core it's a very abstract goal
more concretely its goal is to
authenticate the user so that's the
process where the caller has a secret
and they use that secret to prove that
they are who they claim to be so that in
the case of a regular login the secret
is a password in the case of public
private key they encrypt some token with
the private key send it up public key
decrypts and therefore knows
the sender had the private key in the
first place without ever having to
transmit
so either way
the identity management system here at
its core is a system for authenticating
by handling that cryptography and
providing a trustworthy digital identity
at the end of it to the rest of the
application
now if we layer on what's normally
you'll see the acronym IAM identity and
access management
that layers on further services for
authorization
so authorizations the process where
having an identity
we check if that identity the user can
access particular parts of the system
particular functions particular pieces
of data
you'll see this in the identity
management service they'll often call
that a scope
or a privilege the user has
a privilege operating within a scope I
can read all Financial records
there's my privilege the scope is
financial records in this application
makes sense
we'll touch upon some technologies for
this a little bit later in the episode
but I wanted to talk about a later topic
with that anti-management systems which
is trade-offs between the user
experience and
the actual goals of the energy
management system which as you said was
making sure that we established the
trust and ensure that there is
authorization can you touch upon that
yeah there's two things going on there
one thing thinking of the identity
management the banking account situation
that's certainly not convenient the
identity management eventually probably
has you showing up at a bank teller and
showing them documentation that's there
because it's really important to
identify the person and that's going to
work against the ease of use
which means there's a bit of a ramp
there
the rule is use the identity management
that's appropriate to the data and
process that you have the thing that
you're securing the more you have to
know the more you should do
if you're really only looking to know
that this is the same user that viewed
this page last time
your identity management system might
just be cookie tracking and nothing else
you might have no special code around it
aside from set cookie get cookie check
the number accept that as the person now
on the far side you might all have all
the way through a workflow on the
banking in the middle
people do things like they do captchas
to verify that the person creating
account is a person that'll work until
the computers learn how to interpret the
graphics too late so captchas are
they're challenged at very least right
now as a means of providing security
or they could be multi-factor we'll talk
about I think probably later
multi-factor is a technology
but you'll run into that and your phone
text messages when you log in in order
to validate that at very least you also
have access to this phone number
so the more you have to do to establish
your identity the bigger a ramp there is
and that can be a bit of a barrier so
it's a trade-off you know folks don't
like multi-factor if they're trying to
sell things
you know their shopping carts get
abandoned
on the other hand you can't really
accept the payment without knowing who's
providing it at some level you've got to
have a credit card or something so you
can charge
so your example of somebody having to go
to the bank to prove identity is really
in the sign up stage right that's where
they are verifying who they are by
actually physical presence
and of course there's a lot of fraud
detection Technologies used during sign
up for services on the cloud
so what is the spectrum between showing
up at the bank and what's implemented in
the sign up you know use a credit card
is one aspect of it what else do people
do to ensure that when you sign up you
are who you say you are there are
various features it will run a gamut
certainly the bank teller that's your
more extreme end and there's those
processes can take days at their worst
you know you're actually getting your
passport is probably the root of all of
that depending where you live
stepping back
there are chains of building Trust
can go through things like you only have
access if another person who knows you
provides you with that access so very
manual you yourself never get the
ability to onboard somebody on boards
you
you probably get the ability to set your
password because you don't want two
people knowing the password that sort of
breaks the system
if it's a little bit more automated they
try things like
introduce another Factor do you have
access to this phone number do you have
access to this device do you have a pass
card or a dongle a little chip that
gives a number when pressed based on a
timer so that there's effectively two
passwords one of which is in your head
the other which is on a chip and then
there's multi-factor and you start
getting into other input devices
biometrics
and finally you know getting less and
less secure text messages a bit less
secure
straight old password and the term the
conditions on your password itself
can ramp up anything from you know
nowadays they try to get make you use 15
characters mix alpha numeric Etc
so we will dive into more detailed
topics but as we are wrapping up this
introduction I'd like just to ask my
last question which is what is identity
as a service what does that mean as
opposed to any identity management
system right so remembering again
there's a gamut here
as I said you can just build it in hey I
have a very very vague idea of who the
user is I can tell the same person's
visited this webpage before not much
else that's just a cookie that's it
built in really nothing there at all
it's stepping back a little okay I've
got a whole identity management
subsystem it may be based on libraries
definitely it's built on crypto
libraries I'm probably not coding those
myself compiled in or maybe I've gone a
little bit further created my own
services
that's been great and it's worked pretty
well it was the industry standard for
years
Federation stretched it a bit further
but now we're in the microservice world
in the microservice world identity
management has split off entirely to
become identity as a service and that's
an identity management service usually a
really well built out one that's run by
someone else so someone else does the
running and hosting big Advantage there
security is constantly moving
having somebody else manage your hosted
cryptography and your factors of
authentication your techniques what's
going on out there it's going to be a
big Advantage for you because it reduces
your part of that to just all I have to
do is conform to their API so I can
recognize the identity when I receive it
so identity is a service the micro
service form of identity management
thank you for that
so in this section maybe let's look at
some of the technology and tools that
have enabled this space
the first I had was saml is that the
right place to start would you describe
what saml is you could flip a coin
there's a lot of ways to start
probably what I would do
is I'd start first with single sign-on
because that's why you have saml
so single sign-on the idea is
I sign on with one identity one password
and then every site I visit thereafter
can use that Authentication
to do its identity management so that's
the Federation case in that case each
individual site has its own little bit
of identity management that trusts the
Federated single sign-on identity
management for identity under particular
conditions that it sets
saml was
it was the original guy in this space
so saml it's a specification involving
identity providers and service providers
the identity provider in this is the
identity management system
service provider those are your
individual Cloud applications out there
in the world and they arrange to
exchange public keys and patterns of
interaction such that in the most common
flow you'll go to your end cloud service
it'll say I need to authenticate this
person and redirect them to a login page
that login page will be provided by your
saml provider the identity provider at
the saml service it will do the login
page handling and send back a page with
a assertion about the identity of the
user that just logged in then the cloud
application will take that identity turn
it into a current session continue on
there's also a form that works with just
regular web service calls
involving Bearer tokens where it
basically it creates that end credential
and sends it along with the service
request so that's saml going from there
because I can sort of guess and because
it's so related oauth 2 has pretty much
replaced saml with modern Services oauth
2 that's what you're seeing when
some site says you can log in and create
your account directly or you can sign in
using Google
and you use your Google account that's
an oauth 2. oauth 2 has a two-legged and
a three-legged form
the two-legged form it looks a lot like
saml there is a identity management
system it handles that login page it's
got a trust relationship setup so that
post the authentication on the login
sends along a token this time JWT Bearer
token or usually a JWT definitely a
bearer token on the header of your HTTP
request and the cloud application uses
that in order to determine the identity
of the caller
so there's also three-legged oauth which
it's like it adds one more step in which
the identity provider can actually
before finishing the login
can call out to that cloud provider and
just check on the person hey I received
a request for this person looks okay to
me what you think about it you establish
any state you need to do do any checks
you need to do come back to me and then
I'll return log and succeeded so it
gives the the cloud a bit more control
over what's going on potentially so this
is definitely covered in detail in
episode 376 on API security with or2
however
as we're talking about this where does
open ID connect fit in so openid
actually Builds on oauth 2.
and adds a few more things that you can
do that's its main purpose in the
universe a few more things that you can
do once you have the authenticated user
so extra calls to get the digital
effects about the digital identity
and supporting setup in the background
for it so think of it as an add-on
okay so we talked about the SSO and how
we started with saml and then evolved to
oauth and in response to some previous
questions you did mention multi-factor
authentication do you want to cover that
in a little bit more detail now it gets
more exciting when you think about
things that have changed
so just to take you there multi-factor
authentication so we've already talked
about how you have multi-factor
authentication when your authentication
provides two proofs that you are who you
say you are they've got to be
independent from each other it's no use
to ask a person for two passwords
because heck why not just make them give
you a longer password same thing has to
be two entirely different mechanisms
sources of Truth most common one is a
device in your possession and the
password in your head so multi-factor
exciting in that there are some changes
here a standard called 502 is out there
for what's called passwordless
authentication and it is in fact a form
of multi-factor so there's some room and
change going on there but boils down to
the same thing we have the identity of
the device
involved what 502 does is it allows the
device to register and for the device to
handle login
in an automated fashion and it
stipulates that the device must when it
needs credentials check with you and
because these are devices and our
devices are better and better all the
time it can do things like check
Biometrics your face your fingerprint so
we go from a secret in your head
to a physical factor and a biometric you
know a personal Factor
making the whole password experience
both more seamless and really really
hard much harder than with just a simple
password for someone else to figure out
things have suddenly evolved in that
area with this new technology
so this is about authentication these
tools and Technology support the
Authentication
in terms of access or Access Control can
you just cover the broad spectrum of
what policies are used there or what
roles what's the difference between a
policy based system versus a role-based
system yeah
so building up from well all of these
things sort of occurred all at once in
real life
however
we really started the world most
applications once to get into access
management they start with really
statements of privileges in terms of
their authorization so I have the user I
know who he is what can he do started
out with this person this digital
identity has the following permissions
to do things in my system privileges you
can read records he can create records
of this type he can use this function
that was great but there was a ton of
privileges hanging around you know even
a pretty simple application can quickly
grow privileges especially if you've
been building for a few years you start
to get hundreds thousands of these
things significant functions that you
might want one person to do where
another person can't could you just give
an example
privilege can read a record of a type
that would be an example
so to organize this all
people created rules and roles they
mapped that basically to your position
in a business
so a vice president could have the
following permissions vice presidents
they can read Financial records
you know Frontline sales guy maybe they
can't
maybe they can only create them they
can't read them thereafter
so role management it grouped privileges
into a container it then gave that
container the role to the individual and
you'll find with identity management and
identity and access management systems
especially
that people will split things up and
they'll often put the role in the
identity and access management system
and keep the privilege
for their own cloud application and that
gives them the flexibility to add more
privileges easily
while having that role out there that
people can Federate and work with and
you know I I have two VPS and a hundred
sales people okay so that's the part
that they wanted external as opposed to
internal
that's great but the problem was
we often have especially data that has
attributes that are important to the way
it is used
so ownership would be the simplest case
so what we did is we invented attribute
based Access Control ABAC
in attribute-based Access Control you
still have those Privileges and
permissions but they're relative to
something
that's on the data itself
so
as a vice president I can read all
Financial records
as a director
I can read Financial records in this
division
and the division goes on the record and
the rule for how do you get this
division that goes into your system
so divisional read access would be my
privilege
and the attribute that it's based on is
the division on the financial record
that's great as you can tell I'm kind of
hard coding that all in there just to
keep access base Access Control simple
so really quickly people invented
policy-based access control and what
policy-based Access Control did is it
said all right now we need another
component
that's going to provide a small little
language interpreter and that's going to
take our Privileges and our attributes
from access based control maybe our
roles we're going to mix them all
together we're going to allow operators
so and or not inclusion exclusion based
on attributes of the record and the user
and the role
all mixed together in a language with
rules that get defined separately of the
the actual running system you pass those
factors in it gives you an answer yes no
for you can do this do this thing as
this person with this piece of data so
policy-based Access Control
and that really is now
let's call it the state of the art but
there's even developments there that's
certainly the most built up
form of authorization thank you Nick so
we've covered some of the technology
that has
spurred this space or you know sadly
been key requirements that have evolved
now into identity management systems and
identity as a service
I'd like to now focus a little bit on
what has changed
in this space recently so you mentioned
some key progress on multi-factor
Authentication
my next question is going to be around a
word that I hear more and more which is
zero trust how is that related to
identity management systems
okay so I would say that really has been
two very exciting things and that Fido
that's exciting thing number one
exciting thing number two and they play
together
and taken together they're exciting
because of a reason and I'll Circle back
to that
so zero trust that's exciting thing
number two
so under zero trust
there's the Assumption we have when we
write Cloud applications that our Cloud
application is sitting behind a firewall
and the firewall is structured it's
going to keep everything bad out
and that's true and good and necessary
don't put a cloud application out there
without putting some level of network
protection around it you won't last long
however it's not great there's been a
number of very public incidents where
through social engineering people
managed to get programs on the internal
network of a company system and because
it's sitting there in that internal
Network and because all of the internal
applications were trusting that firewall
to protect them that program had Free
Run
so there's been tackles on food supply
attacks on gas pipelines all using these
attacks on banks in other countries all
using these mechanisms Australia
recently had a health care attack
so what's evolved in response is zero
trust Network architecture and the zero
trust philosophy
under zero trust your internal Services
behind that firewall they don't trust
their Network anymore
they assume that it's entirely possible
for someone to get an application some
agent onto that Network
find their service and start making
calls
so zero trust requires that your
internal services
have Authentication
have a strong sense of user identity
have a strong centralized service for
user identity and have multi-factor
authentication in that the request the
caller the device from which the call is
being made data possibly that's being
requested
and even what they call Network
intelligence security intelligence so
settings fed in by a system
administrator possibly dynamically about
other things they've discovered hey this
module has been compromised can control
that access decision
so zero trust really sophisticated takes
it past that firewall doesn't get rid of
the firewall but it means that our
internal Services as Cloud providers
are they're suitable for being exposed
externally
they behave as if they are exposed
the U.S federal government has gone you
know let's call it all in on this
they're a very strong Advocate the
Office of Management and budget has in
the FED in their fed ramp program which
is their set of standards for making
purchasing decisions especially related
around security and management of cloud
application Services they've set a set
of zero trust security goals and
required all federal agencies to meet
them by 2024. and that includes every
Federal agency is expected to take one
of their moderate internal applications
and make it zero trust internet exposed
as part of that deadline so you know
real application at the federal
government level
governments are supposed to be slower
than the rest of us
so you can tell this is across the chasm
from early adopters into now big
businesses going this way how of all
these regulations impacted the space has
it just made it more
imperative to use identity management
system rather than a homegrown approach
or is there more
so I mean there's really been two things
going on
in that
when it comes to Consumer identity the
regulation has been really important for
driving up the standard it's now you
want to be really careful about how
you're dealing with your identity
because if you fall behind a government
with a just a regular person's identity
the government will stand up for them
and come after you so that's a big deep
pocket that will come in and find you so
it becomes a real business concern in
your Cloud to keep right up to date if
you're not confident with doing that
yourself you're probably wise to get an
identity as a service an identity
management system
that's one factor the other Factor on
the Enterprise side sending aside the
medium ground of the government itself
and fed ramp on the Enterprise side
people have to buy insurance for their
risks and there's been a lot of security
issues lately so what's happened is the
insurance rates for cyber security
have doubled in the last year
approximately
talking to people in the industry I know
of companies I have talked with people
who because of their insurance needs and
their need to have operating insurance
for their business while maintaining
internet connection using the internet
as part of their business not as a
software provider in a completely
separate industry the insurance has
forced them to move from having an
internal I.T shop for everything to
using a cloud provider does the cloud
provider can provide a workup of iso to
7001 it can make the standards and
certifications
it has the backing to do security
incident event management so seam
s-i-e-m you'll run into that so the
cloud provider is basically being forced
on forces of strong word but strongly
indicated if you want to keep your
insurance policy
affordable
and that's passed that's already
happened now they're coming back and
doing their renewals and the insurance
providers saying that great but have you
turn a multi-factor authentication and
when zero trust is out there they're
going to say that's great but it is your
provider or all of your providers zero
trust and if you can't do those things
they're not going to cover you and if
you have even the slightest wrapping
over top of it your service is dependent
on their services and you have due
diligence
responsibility to ensure that they're
doing their part and then you're doing
your little part on top of it
so the whole world is pushing towards
professionalization
of identity management
kind of long past for crypto you can
make up your own crypto art but a
regulator is not going to accept it
until you sit down and you prove it very
rigidly
so it just doesn't happen anymore you
know they get mathematicians to do it
so there are multiple vendors so this
next question is from standpoint of an
Enterprise that is using multiple Cloud
applications and multiple SAS
applications
what is the experience there like if I
have SAS applications from multiple
vendors is there any attempt to have a
common int management system or is it a
fact of life that you would have
different identities for each of these
well remembering that your digital
identity it's just a record right
don't get too hung up on one identity
being one record
yeah I can be represented in many many
many records each saying something
slightly different about me but would
still be my one identity as long as I've
got single sign-on that brings me
between those identity management
systems
and that's what's happening in the
situation where you know two windows one
identity
if it's actually two windows in a
browser one identity there's a thing
called C surf csrf that they try not to
allow data to pass between two windows
it can lead to certain kinds of attacks
and there are counter measures but it is
very common
for one internet application
to have an interface that directly or
indirectly brings up services from
another internet application and then
uses single sign-on
uses Federated identities at some level
to access both services in some
orchestration or coordination of work
you're going to run into this really
commonly as developers we're all really
used to this now if we're using one of
the big cloud providers
they all now have tens some maybe over
hundreds of services that all have a
single point of authentication each one
of those Individual Services knows
something about you as a user but
there's one identity in access
management system for setting up the
cloud that operates across all of them
let's talk a little bit from the
perspective of the developers and the
teams for the next few minutes has that
changed the structure of the teams you
know we structure nowadays as devops
team where there's a certain level of
expertise expected within the team but
there can be Central teams as well has
all this Evolution changed how teams are
structured and what is needed from the
devs and Ops folks on the teams
so you know way back in the day you'll
definitely remember that I burned you
guys in security a lot I've heard all my
teams continuously on security a lot
and I think that's the world we're in so
the term people use is devsec Ops I have
to admit I'm not a big fan of the term
devsecops because I've always believed
if you're doing development and
operations you had better be doing
security
from the very get go and that remains
true that's one factor going on here
that remains true so serious development
serious operations you should be
building insecurity
so from the devsecops practice means
there are a few things that you should
be doing with respect to identity
management first of all think of your
Cloud application break it into its two
main parts there's a control plane and
there's a data plane back up to the
basics of cloud Theory here control
plane that's the thing that can start
stop Services install applications
control resources manage network
configuration set up how the application
behaves
your data plane takes those policies
runs them against data so it's a much
more static in terms of the components
it runs it uses rules to decide how many
compute nodes are going to be running
this process or that process
and it only accepts data from these
sources and it only versus serves data
to these other things
you want to look at your Cloud platform
providing an identity management system
built-in identity management
capabilities
that are strong preferably multi-factor
with a strong amount of physical
ownership so often it has been up to now
dongles but you know Fido's going to
start playing in there
things like pass cards by dongle you
know some physical device a reader on
your system a USB chip you plug in it
gives you a dynamically generated
password
that changes over time and therefore
very hard to replicate
you'll need that in your control plane
you should not build a cloud-facing
application without that level of
strength good news
really easy to do all the cloud major
Cloud providers are already doing that
and if your cloud provider doesn't
provide a service that allows it you're
going to find that there are great
vendors out there that provide systems
that you can install to add that level
of access control on your control plane
secondly well first before I step off
that devops wise this means that your
very first thing you're doing you're
setting up your development environment
you're already in identity and access
management don't skip on that section
pay attention to it set it up so that
you have proper security control it's
going to be good experience for you
moving forward and your teams are going
to have to know how to interact with
their Cloud platforms console which
means interacting with security
so yeah it's got harder the skills have
gotten different
but also Cloud platforms are there and
in a way they're making it easier again
so they are taking a lot of the
professional level of identity
management
for the control plane and they're
putting it in the provider itself
second thing it's a really good time
identity management wise to start
thinking about zero trust
if you're building applications for the
federal government you're already
looking at fedramp and you're probably
already looking at this
now there are vendors out there and
people are in the process of building
their zero trust offerings
but it's a good time to start looking
and to start thinking about if I'm
building a microservice it used to be
that I would set it up and
not authenticate at all hey it's on an
internal Network nothing will ever reach
this thing except for you know my friend
who's in the cubicle beside me is
writing another service is going to call
mine that's just stop thinking that way
start thinking about your microservices
need authentication that's got to be
built into them and that now means that
the smallest component that you have in
your Cloud architecture has
authentication in front of it knows who
that user is and is dealing possibly
with a policy management system for its
authorization so look for those
components or the capability to
introduce those components and think
about the parts of your system that
you're hand building right now that you
may want to refactor and replace later
don't over build build for what you need
but definitely Now's the Time to start
thinking of it except if you're in
fedramp time to start doing so you
mentioned Siam or security information
and event management
what else should people be thinking
about in terms of monitor
addresses and risk management yeah
you're thinking exactly along the same
lines as me so third thing you should
think about doing
security incident event management so
what that is is no matter what you do
you should start with the assumption
that somebody's going to abuse your
system
and that might actually be a straight
outright attack or it might be that your
system you've built something that it
kind of feels like
you missed something it almost feels
like an attack when the customer goes
and uses it so
the one I've encountered not a lot but I
have encountered it put in a service
customers use it in a way and at a
frequency you never anticipated it doses
you your systems now in a recovery mode
receiving extreme usage is this an
attack or is it not
security incident event management you
have to start by building in when you
build your applications the assumption
that abuse is going to occur and you're
going to have to track it back to the
agent that is the source of the abuse
and preferably track it back to a person
and what's more you're going to need to
stop that person that agent without
stopping everyone so build that in now
your development team should be thinking
about hey when the abuse comes we check
here
and then if we find abuse we look here
to see how to isolate it and then we go
here to turn that off leave everything
else running
makes sense it's a lot of a lot of times
it seems like a lot to do you've got
platform engineering coming along after
you and they've definitely picked up the
cloud side so what you really need to do
is think about how you're going to fit
into those pieces there are logging
tools out there that will help you with
the log capture and secure management of
logs for Siem
there are consoles out there that will
help you monitor usage pick up on events
that occur so it's really a matter of
figuring out how does your application
in its own running surface events and
logs that allow you to trace back so
it's really much more closely related to
what you were actually doing in the
first place you've just got to buy the
components and make your application use
them
so starting to wrap up learning if you
evaluate int management platform vendors
how do you do that what steps do you use
so I basically I divide it in three the
very first thing you've got to think
about is your Cloud platform
your identity and access management for
your Cloud platform the infrastructure
on which you're running your application
that's a requirement
start there if you don't have it then
that's disqualifying you can't use that
platform
it's got a change or you've got to
switch platforms
as I've said that's actually pretty easy
the major Cloud platforms they're well
ahead of us here and they've already set
it up such that you can so it's a matter
of exercising next level down think
about your internal Network architecture
this is fairly new and recent
think about how your Individual Services
are going to integrate into your
identity management system
your logging system although that's
somewhat separate for Siem
ease of use is a big concern there
you're going to want to prototype and
figure out what you're using if you're
building exclusively for one Cloud
platform you may have strong indicators
in terms of what you're doing there
already in the family of applications
that that system provides
but people have been substituting
components and one of the big drivers is
ease of use
regardless stop picking components that
are going to prevent you from doing this
stop writing code that's going to
prevent you from eventually achieving
zero trust it's coming
then last not necessarily in that order
think of all three at the same time
external Authentication
how are you going to meet the users
where they are
what is the level of identity management
that's appropriate for the data that
you're handling
and the processing that you're providing
don't undervalue your data if you're
building an internet service you're
building a cloud application there's
something about it that's valuable
right so think about what it would mean
if that data was compromised corrupted
if a password is lost if
somebody just circumvented the whole
thing think about that think about how
you provide your customers with the
ability to sign in in a smooth way and
what identity management system they're
using
so a lot of authentication people are
signing on using Google or Facebook or
one of the other major internet
applications they have an identity as a
service provider there it integrates
often using the auth
you want to pick up provide that on top
of your basic authentication if you're
going to allow people to sign in without
going through that system
and if you're dealing with Enterprises
you should think about well if they buy
one of the big identity providers
and they decide to Federate with me does
my identity management system support
that Federation is it giving me the
right amount of policy control such that
I can take that Enterprise and provide a
cloud service to them and continue to
provide cloud services to other
Enterprises who might decide to approach
this whole thing differently you know
other identity management using your
identity management could be many things
so look at all three break it down that
way do consider cycle time ease of
development that remains very very
important if you can't turn out software
because you can't get the apis to work
that's a big concern but try to pick
your components to enable that internal
Network authentication or at least have
a road map to it to provide strong
platform authentication and to meet that
customer where they are in their
identity management
you know whether it's they individually
in a 502 or they as an organization with
a saml identity provider wanting you to
be a sample service provider thank you
Nick so how should folks contact you the
easiest way to reach out to me is via my
LinkedIn profile that's Nicholas Manson
n-i-c-a-h-o-l-i-s-m-a-n-s-o-n at
LinkedIn okay sounds great we'll try to
put that in the show notes
is there anything you'd like to cover
that we haven't talked about today on
this topic there are a ton of things in
security that we could discuss
once you've picked your platform in as
part of considering the platform that
you're developing in pick up their best
practice documents give it a good read
remember that everything you develop it
and all of security gets a lot easier if
you do it early this is one of those
places where debt just piles up real
quick and it can prevent you from
releasing and it can do it the very last
moment and with a lot of pushback
from an auditor if you're going to try
to do a ISO
[Music]
0001 standard certification
so instead pick up the best practices
start implementing right away think of
it as everything that isn't a regular
day-to-day thing that the operators do
via standard operating procedure
that's development pick it up then do it
then
otherwise have a lot of fun with this of
course security is of course the part
we're all anxious to write yeah you know
take it seriously Push It Forward it
won't be as bad as you think sounds
great thank you so much for being on the
show to the naked it was great talking
to you on this complex topic yeah thanks
a lot cancer it was great being here
thanks all for listening
thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by
your police software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at
sc-radio.net
feedback you can comment on each episode
on the website or reach us on LinkedIn
Facebook Twitter or through our slack
Channel at SC radio dot slack.com you
can also email us at team sc-radio.net
this and all other episodes of SC radio
is licensed under created Commons
license 2.5
thanks for listening